Gabriela Ramirez

CONTACT		
Austin, Texas	linkedin.com/in/gabrielasramirez	⊠ gabyrmz1994@gmail.com
956.458.3366	github.com/GabrielaSRamirez94	gabyrmz.com

PROJECTS

THE BRICK MANAGEMENT

A client project for a small modeling agency. I am currently working on the design as well as the construction of their website.

github.com/GabrielaSRamirez94/brick-management

SPEAK

Speak is an augmentative and alternative communication web application designed to promote language development and grow communication skills in non-verbal people. I primarily focused on front-end development and UI/UX design.

github.com/GabrielaSRamirez94/speak

O STACK OVERFLOW CLONE

This is a project with a similar functionality to Stack Overflow. Users are able to post questions, add comments, and up or downvote questions and comments. I primarily worked on user authentication along with front-end development and UI/UX design.

github.com/GabrielaSRamirez94/ stackoverflow-clone

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Technical Skills

Javascript	Sinatra	SQLite3
HTML	AJAX	Active Record
CSS	Jasmine	Bootstrap
Ruby	RSpec	Heroku
Rails 5	PostgreSQL	API Consumption
Github	JSON	Agile Workflow

EDUCATION

O Graduated 2016

Bachelor of Science in Biology

St. Mary's University San Antonio, Texas

EXPERIENCE

O From June 2017 to November 2017 DEV BOOTCAMP | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Immersive web development program where I gained a variety of technical skills. Applied these skills directly to daily challenges and group projects developing full stack web applications. Worked in an agile environment and practiced teamwork putting to use the program's unique Engineering Empathy curriculum.

From June 2016 to July 2017 COOLWAY | ASSISTANT MANAGER

Worked one on one with clients during consultations and procedures in a medical aesthetics clinic. Managed all social media channels and platforms.

O From June 2015 to May 2016

ST. MARY'S UNIVERSITY | RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Researched metabolism for variety of preying mantis species. Monitored and assessed the needs of various animals and insects.

Interpreted data and assembled figures for journal publication and poster presentation.

From May 2012 to April 2015 VARIOUS PRIVATE PRACTICES | INTERN

Measured patient's vitals and aided in basic wound-care treatments alongside nurses. Discussed individual cases including diagnoses and prognoses with the lead physician. Translated for Spanish-speaking patients when working with nurse practitioner.